compsci.ca 2017-12-11

# 

## Privacy Policy

Computer Science Canada knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. By visiting the Computer Science Canada website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy.

### What Does This Privacy Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy covers Computer Science Canada's treatment of personal information that Computer Science Canada gathers when you are on a Computer Science Canada website and when you use Computer Science Canada services.

This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Computer Science Canada does not own or control, or to individuals that Computer Science Canada does not employ or manage.

### What Personal Information About Users Does Computer Science Canada Collect?

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a friendly, customized, and efficient experience. We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website. We do not process this information in a way that is incompatible with the purpose for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by you. We collect the following types of information from our users:

  1. Information You Provide to Us:  
We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features. The personal information you provide is used for such purposes as: 

    * Registration: In order for you to use Computer Science Canada services, such as submitting new topics to the website, you must complete a registration form. As part of this registration form, we require your email address. 

  2. Automatic Information: 

    * We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. Computer Science Canada automatically receives and records certain "traffic data" on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, Computer Science Canada cookie information, and the page you requested. Computer Science Canada uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the websites. 

  3. Computer Science Canada may also add on any page and display the total counts that page has been viewed. This includes member profile pages and individual user views. 

  4. Social sharing of data: Computer Science Canada allows other users to browse topics, posts and comments that you have submitted or commented on. This information is made available via your member profile, or within the permalink URL of the topic or artical in which you performed the action on. Computer Science Canada may choose to post this data on other site features in the future. 

  5. Profile information: Computer Science Canada allows other users to browse your full name, location, and instant messaging URL, within your member profile should you provide this information. 

  6. Syndication: Computer Science Canada allows for the RSS syndication of most of its public content within the website 

  7. Computer Science Canada will allow 3rd parties access to all Computer Science Canada data this is already publicly available. Computer Science Canada will forever keep private passwords hashs. 

  8. Many companies offer programs that help you to visit websites anonymously. While Computer Science Canada will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these programs are available. 

  9. Computer Science Canada may view, edit or delete private messages for reasons of controling spam, stoping adubes and admistarting the system. If you do not whont you private messages viewable to staff we sugest you use the encryption function in the private messages site.

  10. Computer Science Canada may use your e-mail address to send you information realting to changes in our polices and services. Also Computer Science Canada allows users other users to send you e-mail through the site by default. This can be disabled in your profile.

  11. Computer Science Canada allows other users to view your online status and what page you are current viewing by deafult. This can be pervented by changing your mode to hidden in your profile however staff will still be able to see what page you a view and your online status.

  12. Computer Science Canada may view, edit or delete users personal notes for reasons of controlling spam, stoping abuse and administering the system.

  13. Computer Science Canada will publically display your birthday, gender, zodiac symbol, local time, website, and other information in your profile if provided.

  14. Computer Science Canada will publically display your bits and karma rating to other users of the site as well as your post count and the date your joined the comunity.

  15. All files uploaded to Computer Science Canada's sites maybe publically available for viewing.

  16. All chat sessions in the Computer Science Canada chat room (irc room) maybe recorded and publicaly displayed on the site.

  17. All editing actions on the Computer Science Canada wiki will be recored and publicly viewable. 

  18. Computer Science Canada runs 3rd party ads and scripts that may record user statics. Computer Science Canada is not responsible for what information these 3rd partys maybe collecting and has no control over there privacy polices.

  19. Donations to Computer Science Canada maybe publically reported, including name of the donator, the amount and the time of donation.

  20. All content and posts upload or submited to our service should be considered public. Theses posts and submissions make up the content of our sites and should be considered a matter of public record.

### What About Cookies?

  * Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. Computer Science Canada cookies do not collect personal information other then what topics you have read as to keep them read, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or email address is. 

  * The "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We strongly recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because cookies enable you to take advantage of some of Computer Science Canada's most attractive features. 

  * Some of our business partners may use cookies on our website (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

### Will Computer Science Canada Share Any of the Information it Receives?

Information about our users is an integral part of our business. We neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone. We share your personal information only as described below.

  * **Computer Science Canada Personnel:**   
Computer Science Canada personnel (including, for the avoidance of doubt, consultants, contractors and/or volunteers) may have access to user information while carrying out their duties in the normal course of Computer Science Canada business. 

  * **Business Transfers:**   
In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Computer Science Canada, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred. 

  * **Protection of Computer Science Canada and Others:**  
We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with that law; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Computer Science Canada, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

  * **With Your Consent:**  
Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your personal information may be shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to prevent the sharing of this information by opting out. 

  * **stopforumspam.com**  
CompSci.ca will share the username, e-mail address and IP of users we consider to be spammers with the site [stopforumspam.com](http://stopforumspam.com./). CompSci.ca is not responsible for what information is shared by stopforumspam.com. What constitutes spaming is left solely to the determination of our staff, moderators, and automated systems. Any user may be listed as a spammer and have there information shared with stopforumspam.com at any time. 

### Is Information About Me Secure?

  * Your Computer Science Canada accounts information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You need to work to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer. 

  * Only employees who need personal information to perform a specific job are granted access to it. All passwords are hashed and not readable to employees. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices. 

### What Information Can I Access?

You can access your personal information on our website and correct, amend, or delete information that is inaccurate. Upon logging in visit your user profile setting page to update your information. 

### What Choices Do I Have?

  * As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information, but then you may be unable to use certain features on our website, such as posting new topics. 

  * In some cases you may be able to add or update certain information on pages, such as those listed in the "What Personal Information About Users Does Computer Science Canada Collect?" section above. When you update information, however, we often maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. 

  * You may request deletion of your Computer Science Canada account by emailing us at support@compsci.ca however your submitted content will remain. In some cases this may remove your username from posts, however this is not gratined. Poof that you own the account and a small administrative fee may be required. 

  * As explained earlier, the "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. Please note, however, that if your browser does not accept cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of some of our attractive features. 

  * By uploading any content or submitting any posts to our service you grant us all rights necessary to use and publish your content/submissions (as outlined in our ToU). Posts and submissions should be considered a matter of public record (as they are viewable by anyone) and permanent in most cases. Post may be removed at a staff members discretion, for violation of the ToU, violation of laws, copyright infringement, or in special cases user request for removal of their own content. Users may request removal of their posts by contacting an admin, however proof of ownership of the account and a small administrative fee per post maybe required.

### Administrative Fees

Due to a large number of requests for post and account removals, we are forced to charge a small administrative fee for our staff to manually process personal removal requests (note that theses fees do not apply to ToU or copyright violations). Theses fees maybe waved at the staff members discretion but may not be more then the amounts listed. Users must prove that they are owners of the account before a removal request maybe processed. 

  * **Account Removal:** $10 per account. Note that this does not include removal of any posts and simply disables the account and removes the username from posts.

  * **Post Removal:** $5 per post. Note that the post will be removed and replaced with a notice detailing that the post was removed by the user and a small description of what was removed. Other user's posts quoting your removed post may not be removed.

### Can Children Use Computer Science Canada's Services?

You must be 13 years and older to register to use the Computer Science Canada websites. As a result, Computer Science Canada does not specifically collect information about children.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Computer Science Canada may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the current Privacy Policy. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, a new copy of the policy will be uploaded in it's place and we may notify you by posting an announcement on the Computer Science Canada website or e-mailing you so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances if any, it is disclosed. It is the user's responsibility to stay apprised of changes to the privacy policy and ToU and contact the staff of any objections or their information will be dealt with under the new policy

### Conditions of Use

If you decide to visit Computer Science Canada websites, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of Ontario law.

### Effective Date of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 7, 2007

Last updated on November 12th, 2011
